<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://ml4sts.com</id>
  <title>  The Machine Learning for Socio-Technical Systems Lab at University of Rhode Island</title>
  <updated>2024-08-27T16:17:44.381811+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://ml4sts.com"/>
  <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.org/" version="0.10.33.post1">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-01-18-aisummit/</id>
    <title>Dr Brown presented on What is AI at the Academic Summit for URI Faculty</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="ablog-post-excerpt docutils container"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-01-18-aisummit/"/>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-01-23-ugsp24/</id>
    <title>Welcome to new undergraduates Lani, Noah,  Trevor, and Rohan</title>
    <updated>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="ablog-post-excerpt docutils container"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lani will be working on understanding how problem formulation is/not described in current
ML research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trevor and Noah will be joining Brendan to work on internal tooling for the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-01-23-ugsp24/"/>
    <summary>Lani will be working on understanding how problem formulation is/not described in current
ML research.Trevor and Noah will be joining Brendan to work on internal tooling for the lab.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-04-mc-wids/</id>
    <title>Dr. Brown gave a keynote at Middlebury College Women in Data Science conference</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="ablog-post-excerpt docutils container"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt;  Data Science Skills in Unexpected Places&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abstract&lt;/strong&gt; Data science is a highly interdisciplinary pursuit, combining computer science and statistics with domain expertise to make sense of data. This means as data scientists we must work closely with domain experts or develop enough domain expertise of our own for each project.  In this talk, I will share the story behind a few data science projects I have done: how high school social studies helped me develop a learning PTSD diagnosis, undergraduate advanced writing helps me measure understanding of fairness in AI, and how student leadership experiences help me design tools for data scientists to build better models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-04-mc-wids/"/>
    <summary>title  Data Science Skills in Unexpected Placesabstract Data science is a highly interdisciplinary pursuit, combining computer science and statistics with domain expertise to make sense of data. This means as data scientists we must work closely with domain experts or develop enough domain expertise of our own for each project.  In this talk, I will share the story behind a few data science projects I have done: how high school social studies helped me develop a learning PTSD diagnosis, undergraduate advanced writing helps me measure understanding of fairness in AI, and how student leadership experiences help me design tools for data scientists to build better models.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-22-nsbe50/</id>
    <title>Dr. Brown will present a workshop at NSBE 50</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="ablog-post-excerpt docutils container"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will be a hands on workshop to build a profile website using github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-22-nsbe50/"/>
    <summary>The workshop will be a hands on workshop to build a profile website using github pages.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-29-fireside/</id>
    <title>Dr Brown will participate in the AI lab Fireside chat series</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="ablog-post-excerpt docutils container"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; How to anticipate risks in AI-enhanced research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abstract&lt;/strong&gt; ML-powered AI is increasingly appearing in all areas of research. However, ML is still in many ways a research output, more of a prototype than a polished, reliable, product. Even commercially released systems, because they are software, can be released without the same rigorous testing that commercially available research equipment has been traditionally be subject to. In this talk, I will draw connections between the ML research process and potential risks in applied ML and use of commercial AI in research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://ml4sts.com/news/2024-03-29-fireside/"/>
    <summary>title How to anticipate risks in AI-enhanced researchabstract ML-powered AI is increasingly appearing in all areas of research. However, ML is still in many ways a research output, more of a prototype than a polished, reliable, product. Even commercially released systems, because they are software, can be released without the same rigorous testing that commercially available research equipment has been traditionally be subject to. In this talk, I will draw connections between the ML research process and potential risks in applied ML and use of commercial AI in research.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
